Asian Applied and Decorative Arts Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Asian Applied and Decorative Arts Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 2
Yale University Arts Library
11.6
28 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian applied and decorative arts. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged by country or region. The country or region is further divided by medium and chronological period. Individual artists listed, if known.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian applied and decorative arts. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Decorative arts -- Asia; Photographs; Reproductions
- Miscellaneous Asian Countries.
  - Bali., 1 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Burma., 2 (Box 1)
  - Cambodia., 37 (Box 1)
  - Ceylon., 4 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 1 (Box 1)
    - Sigiriya., 3 (Box 1)
  - Indo-China., 10 (Box 1)
  - Java., 4 (Box 1)
  - Korea., 28 (Box 2)
  - Nepal., 8 (Box 2)
  - Siam (Thailand)., 110
    - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 2)
    - VIII Century., 6 (Box 2)
    - IX Century., 4 (Box 2)
    - X Century., 9 (Box 2)
    - XII Century., 22 (Box 3)
    - XIII Century., 15 (Box 3)
    - XIV Century., 16 (Box 3)
    - XV Century., 5 (Box 3)
    - XVI Century., 27 (Box 4)
  - Tibet., 41 (Box 4)
- China, India and Japan.
  - Minor Arts., 1988
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 5)
    - Armour and Weapons., 10 (Box 5)
      - China., 5 (Box 5)
      - India, 2 (Box 5)
      - Japan., 3 (Box 5)
    - Calligraphy., 491
      - China., 484
        - Miscellaneous works., 15 (Box 5)
          - Known artists., 6 (Box 5)
            - Chang Ch'ung-Ho, XX C., 1 (Box 5)
            - K'ang Yu-Wei, 1858-1927., 1 (Box 5)
            - K'ung Te-Ch'eng, 1920-., 1 (Box 5)
            - Tung Tso-Pin, -1963., 1 (Box 5)
            - Wang To, Five Dynasties., 1 (Box 5)
            - Wu Ch'ang-Shih, 1844-1927., 1 (Box 5)
          - Unknown., 9 (Box 5)
        - Six Dynasties., 16 (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous artists., 2 (Box 5)
            - Chung Yao, 151-230., 1 (Box 5)
            - Wang Hsun, 350-401., 1 (Box 5)
          - Individual artists., 14 (Box 5)
            - Wang Hsi-Chih, 344-386., 14 (Box 5)
        - T'ang Dynasty., 83
          - Unknown artists., 9 (Box 5)
          - Known artists., 74
            - Miscellaneous artists., 11 (Box 5)
              - Chang Hsu, active 713-740., 1 (Box 5)
              - Kao Hsien, IX C., 3 (Box 5)
              - Ouyang Hsun, 557-651., 1 (Box 5)
              - Tu Mu, 803-852., 1 (Box 5)
              - Yen Chen-Ch'ing, 709-785., 5 (Box 5)
            - Individual artists., 63
              - Hsu Hao., 3 (Box 5)
              - Hsuan-Tsung, Emperor, 685-762., 8 (Box 5)
              - Huai-Su, monk, 725-785., 20 (Box 6)
              - Lu Chien-Chih., 12 (Box 6)
              - Sun Kuo-T'ing., 20 (Box 6)
        - Sung Dynasty., 149
          - Unknown artists., 7 (Box 6)
          - Known artists., 142
            - Miscellaneous artists., 47 (Box 6)
              - Chang Fang-P'ing., 1 (Box 6)
              - Chang Shang-Ying., 2 (Box 6)
              - Chang Yu., 2 (Box 6)
              - Chao Ling-Chih., 1 (Box 6)
              - Chao Pien., 1 (Box 6)
              - Ch'ien Kung-Fu., 1 (Box 6)
              - Chu Hsi., 4 (Box 6)
              - Fan Ch'un-Jen., 1 (Box 6)
              - Fan Ch'un-Ts'ui., 1 (Box 6)
              - Fan Pai-Lu., 1 (Box 6)
              - Fu Pi., 1 (Box 6)
              - Fu-Yin., 1 (Box 6)
              - Han Chen., 1 (Box 6)
              - Han Chiang., 2 (Box 6)
              - Han I., 1 (Box 6)
              - Hsieh K'o-Chia., 1 (Box 6)
              - Hu Shun-Ch'en, XII C., 1 (Box 6)
              - Kao-tsung., 1 (Box 6)
              - Li Chien-Chung, 945-1013., 1 (Box 6)
              - Li-Tsung, 1203-c.1264, 1 (Box 6)
              - Lu Chia-Wen., 1 (Box 6)
              - Lu Kung-Pi., 1 (Box 6)
              - Lu Ta-Fang., 1 (Box 6)
              - O-Yang Hsiu., 1 (Box 6)
              - Shen Kou., 1 (Box 6)
              - Shih Hao., 1 (Box 6)
              - Su Ch'e., 1 (Box 6)
              - Sung Hsiang., 1 (Box 6)
              - Szu-Ma Kuang., 1 (Box 6)
              - T'ang Chiung., 1 (Box 6)
              - Ts'ai Ching., 1 (Box 6)
              - Ts'ai Shiang., 1 (Box 6)
              - Tuan-Yen., 1 (Box 6)
              - Wang An-Shih., 1 (Box 6)
              - Wang Ch'i-Han, X C., 1 (Box 6)
              - Wang Hsi-Chih., 1 (Box 6)
              - Wen Yen-Po., 1 (Box 6)
              - Wu Chu., 1 (Box 6)
              - Yang Mei-Tzu, c.1200., 2 (Box 6)
              - Yeh Ch'ing-Ch'en., 1 (Box 6)
            - Individual artists., 95 (Box 7)
              - Chao Meng-Chien, 1199-1295., 9 (Box 7)
              - Hsueh Shao-P'eng., 8 (Box 7)
              - Huang T'ing-Chien. 1045-1105., 18 (Box 7)
              - Hui-Tsung, Emperor, 1082-1126., 16 (Box 7)
              - Kao-Tsung, Emperor, 1107-1187., 3 (Box 7)
              - Mi Fu, 1051-1107., 8 (Box 7)
              - Mi Fei, 1051-1107., 19 (Box 7)
              - Su Shih., 9 (Box 7)
              - Yeh-Lu Ch'u-Ts'ai, 1190-1244., 5 (Box 7)
        - Yuan Dynasty., 111 (Box 8)
          - Known artists., 111 (Box 8)
            - Miscellaneous artists., 14 (Box 8)
              - Multiple artists., 2 (Box 8)
              - Chang Chu., 1 (Box 8)
              - Chao Meng-Yu and Yung-Ning., 1 (Box 8)
              - Chao Yung., 1 (Box 8)
              - Chou Po-Wen., 1 (Box 8)
              - Chu Yun-Ming and Yang Hsun-Chi., 1 (Box 8)
              - Kuan Tao-Sheng., 1 (Box 8)
              - Kung Su., 1 (Box 8)
              - Sung K'e., 2 (Box 8)
              - Tung Ch'i-Ch'ang., 1 (Box 8)
              - Yang Chi., 1 (Box 8)
              - Yao Shu., 1 (Box 8)
            - Individual artists., 97 (Box 8)
              - Chang Yu, 1275-1348., 5 (Box 8)
              - Chao Meng-Fu, 1254-1322., 64 (Box 8)
                - Miscellaneous works., 21 (Box 8)
                - Album of Calligraphy by Two Masters., 3 (Box 8)
                - A History of the Lan-t'ing-hsu., 5 (Box 8)
                - Letters., 9 (Box 8)
                - Letters to Master Chung-Feng., 11 (Box 8)
                - A poem by Chu Hsi of the Sung Dynasty., 6 (Box 8)
                - Red Cliff Poems by Su Shih., 8 (Box 8)
              - Hsien-Yu Shu, 1256-1301., 12 (Box 8)
              - K'ang-Li K'uei, Yu Chi, and Jao Chieh., 5 (Box 8)
              - Li K'an, 1245-1320., 6 (Box 8)
              - Lu Chi-Shan., 5 (Box 8)
        - Ming Dynasty., 98 (Box 9)
          - Known artists., 98 (Box 9)
            - Miscellaneous artists., 23 (Box 9)
              - Ch'en Pi., 1 (Box 9)
              - Ch'en Yuan-Su, XVII C., 1 (Box 9)
              - Ch'eng Nan-Yun, c.1403-1436., 1 (Box 9)
              - Hai Jui, 1514-1587., 1 (Box 9)
              - Hsiang Yuan-Pien, 1525-1590., 1 (Box 9)
              - Hsing T'ung, 1551-1612., 1 (Box 9)
              - Hsu Lin, XVI C., 1 (Box 9)
              - Hsu Wei, 1520-1593., 1 (Box 9)
              - Hsueh Ming-I, XVI C., 1 (Box 9)
              - Shen Shih, XVI C., 1 (Box 9)
              - Shen Ts'an., 2 (Box 9)
              - Sung K'o., 1 (Box 9)
              - Sung Kuang, XIV C., 1 (Box 9)
              - Sung Lien., 1 (Box 9)
              - T'ang Yin, 1470-1523., 1 (Box 9)
              - Ts'ai Yu, -1541., 1 (Box 9)
              - Tung Ch'i-Ch'ang, 1555-1636., 5 (Box 9)
              - Wang Ao, 1450-1524., 1 (Box 9)
            - Individual artists., 75 (Box 9)
              - Chu Yun-Ming, 1460-1526., 13 (Box 9)
              - Hsu Wei, 1521-1593., 5 (Box 9)
              - Shen Chou, 1427-1509., 7 (Box 9)
              - Wen Cheng-Ming, 1470-1559, 50 (Box 9)
                - Miscellaneous Locations., 9 (Box 9)
                - New York., 18 (Box 9)
                - Poem, mounted as album., 18 (Box 9)
                - Taichung., 23 (Box 9)
                - Miscellaneous Works., 8 (Box 9)
                - Ten Lessons From The Father of Kao Hsing-Wu., 15 (Box 9)
        - Ch'ing Dynasty., 32 (Box 10)
          - Known artists., 32 (Box 10)
            - Miscellaneous artists., 17 (Box 10)
              - Ch'a Shih-Piao, 1615-1698., 1 (Box 10)
              - Chao Chih-Ch'ien, 1829-1884., 1 (Box 10)
              - Cheng Hsieh, 1693-1765., 1 (Box 10)
              - Ch'ien Feng, 1740-1795., 2 (Box 10)
              - Ho Shao-Chi, 1799-1873., 1 (Box 10)
              - Kuei Fu, 1736-1805., 1 (Box 10)
              - Li T'ieh-Weng, XVII C., 1 (Box 10)
              - Lin Tse-Hsu, 1785-1850., 1 (Box 10)
              - Liu Shih-An., 1 (Box 10)
              - Liu Ying, 1719-1804., 1 (Box 10)
              - Pa-Ta Shan-Jen, 1626-c.1705., 2 (Box 10)
              - Wang Shih-Min, 1592-1680., 1 (Box 10)
              - Weng Fang-Kang., 1 (Box 10)
              - Weng T'ung-Ho, 1830-1904., 1 (Box 10)
              - Wu Ch'ang-Shih, 1844-1927., 1 (Box 10)
            - Individual artists., 15 (Box 10)
              - Chin Nung, 1687-1764., 15 (Box 10)
      - Japan., 7 (Box 10)
        - Unknown artists., 6 (Box 10)
        - Known artists., 1 (Box 10)
          - Saku-Gen, 1501-1579., 1 (Box 10)
    - Ceramics., 520
      - China., 518
        - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 10)
        - Pre-Historic., 42 (Box 10)
        - Shang Dynasty., 13 (Box 11)
        - Chou Dynasty., 7 (Box 11)
        - Han Dynasty., 28 (Box 11)
        - Six Dynasties., 27 (Box 11)
        - Sui Dynasty., 5 (Box 11)
        - T'ang Dynasty., 37 (Box 12)
        - Five Dynasties., 7 (Box 12)
        - Liao Dynasty., 7 (Box 12)
        - Chin Dynasty., 3 (Box 12)
        - Sung Dynasty., 93
          - Miscellaneous works., 41 (Box 12)
          - Celadon ware., 13 (Box 12)
          - Chiao-tan Kuan ware., 5 (Box 13)
          - Ju ware., 10 (Box 13)
          - Kuan ware., 13 (Box 13)
          - Lungchuan ware., 3 (Box 13)
          - Ting ware., 8 (Box 13)
        - Yuan Dynasty., 24 (Box 13)
        - Ming Dynasty., 100 (Box 14)
          - Miscellaneous works., 44 (Box 14)
          - Blue and white ware., 35 (Box 14)
          - Red ware., 8 (Box 14)
          - White ware., 6 (Box 14)
          - Yu-li-hung ware., 7 (Box 14)
        - Ch'ing Dynasty., 112
          - Miscellaneous works., 52 (Box 15)
          - Enameled porcelain., 31 (Box 15)
          - Famille noire., 4 (Box 15)
          - Monochrome., 18 (Box 16)
          - Export porcelain., 7 (Box 16)
      - Japan., 62 (Box 16)
    - Enamel., 14 (Box 16)
      - China., 14 (Box 16)
    - Furniture., 22 (Box 17)
      - China., 20 (Box 17)
      - Japan., 2 (Box 17)
    - Glass., 11 (Box 17)
      - China., 11 (Box 17)
    - Implements., 3 (Box 17)
      - China., 3 (Box 17)
    - Ivory., 11 (Box 17)
      - China., 9 (Box 17)
      - Japan., 2 (Box 17)
    - Jade., 89
      - China., 89
        - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 17)
        - Shang Dynasty., 12 (Box 17)
        - Chou Dynasty., 10 (Box 17)
        - Han Dynasty., 13 (Box 18)
        - Sung Dynasty., 6 (Box 18)
        - Ming Dynasty., 6 (Box 18)
        - Ch'ing Dynasty., 31 (Box 18)
    - Lacquer., 68
      - China., 38 (Box 18)
      - Japan., 30 (Box 19)
    - Masks., 1 (Box 19)
      - Japan., 1 (Box 19)
    - Metalwork., 569
      - China., 548
        - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 19)
        - Suspected forgeries., 13 (Box 19)
        - Shang Dynasty., 135
          - Miscellaneous works., 62 (Box 20)
          - Ku., 12 (Box 20)
          - Kuei., 6 (Box 20)
          - Ting., 20 (Box 21)
          - Tsun., 17 (Box 21)
          - Yu., 18 (Box 21)
        - Chou Dynasty., 229
          - Miscellaneous works., 36 (Box 21)
          - Early Chou Dynasty (Western)., 82 (Box 22)
            - Miscellaneous works., 44 (Box 22)
            - Kuei and Lei., 18 (Box 22)
            - Ting., 10 (Box 22)
            - Tsun., 10 (Box 22)
          - Middle Chou Dynasty., 18 (Box 23)
          - Late Chou Dynasty (Eastern)., 93
            - Miscellaneous works., 59 (Box 23)
            - Bells., 8 (Box 23)
            - Hu., 18 (Box 24)
            - Ting., 8 (Box 24)
        - Han Dynasty., 75 (Box 24)
          - Miscellaneous works., 54 (Box 24)
          - Hu., 12 (Box 24)
          - Mirrors., 9 (Box 24)
        - Six Dynasties., 2 (Box 25)
        - T'ang Dynasty., 58 (Box 25)
        - Sung Dynasty., 4 (Box 25)
        - Ming Dynasty., 9 (Box 25)
        - Ch'ing Dynasty., 12
      - India., 1 (Box 25)
      - Japan., 20 (Box 26)
    - Tapestry., 10 (Box 26)
    - Textiles., 75
      - China., 28 (Box 26)
      - India., 8 (Box 26)
      - Japan., 39 (Box 27)
    - Tun Huang Caves., 91
      - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 27)
      - Caves 1 through 99., 15 (Box 27)
      - Caves 100 through 199., 30 (Box 28)
        - Miscellaneous caves., 19 (Box 28)
        - Cave 120., 4 (Box 28)
        - Cave 140., 7 (Box 28)
      - Caves 200 through 299., 21 (Box 28)
      - Caves 300 through 499., 13 (Box 28)